<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unity on Herain&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://herainic.com/tags/unity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unity on Herain&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 20:19:31 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://herainic.com/tags/unity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why and How I Refactor My AssetBundle Manager</title>
      <link>https://herainic.com/posts/whyandhowirefactormyassetbundlemanager/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2022 20:19:31 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://herainic.com/posts/whyandhowirefactormyassetbundlemanager/</guid>
      <description>Comparing to putting asset inside of Resources folder, using asset bundle system has a lot of benefits. While using resources system, Unity engine will create a index table for all resources inside Resources folder, in order to fasten the speed of Resources.Load. It is really fast but every time we add something into the folder, engine will need to rebuild the table, as the number of resources increase, the table also increase and need a lot of memory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unity Collision Detection</title>
      <link>https://herainic.com/posts/unitycollisiondetection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 14:29:20 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://herainic.com/posts/unitycollisiondetection/</guid>
      <description>About three or four years ago, I was development my first indie game, and my main character have a gun, well if you know something about unity, you know what happened, the bullet go through enemy because of the tunnel effect because of the velocity is too large. At that time I know little about unity so my solution was just slow down the bullet.
However, there is a solution provided by Unity itself somehow I missed it, so I decided to write something about it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
